（竹芋）
（荸荠）
- 好啊 卡萝尔 - 托宾
- Hey, Carol. - Tobin.
你该吃点饼干
You deserve some cookies.
不 孩子们还饿着呢
Oh, no, not with the kids as hungry…
不 有很多 我找到了很多橡子
No, there's plenty. I foraged a lot of acorns.
- 这是粉色的 - 甜菜
- They're pink. - Beets.
- 甜菜 - 能让它们更甜
- Beets? - It's what makes them sweet.
我不大喜欢吃甜菜
I never was much of a beet kind of guy.
你别废话了直接吃行吗 混蛋
Will you just put it in your mouth, jerk.
这是我吃过的最好吃的甜菜橡子饼干
They're the best beet and acorn cookies I've ever eaten.
你在耍我吗
Are you screwing with me?
没有
No.
真的
Seriously.
太好吃了
They're amazing.
他们回来了
They're back!
去找奥利维亚
Get Olivia.
她该登记我们带回来的东西
She should inventory what we have.
叫她在储藏室见我们
We'll meet her at the pantry.
- 你们弄到了食物吗 - 是的
- You have food? - Yeah.
足够再撑一个月
Enough for another month.
叫大家一小时内到教堂集合
I need everybody in the church in an hour.
出什么事了
What is it?
我们一会儿说
We'll talk about it.
瑞克 怎么了
Rick, what's going on?
我们得战斗了
We're gonna have to fight.
那事过后有一阵子了
It's been a while.
几周了
Weeks.
- 什么事 - 聊天
- Since what? - Since we talked.
我们在那牢房里只聊天了吗
That's what we did in that cell? We talked.
你为什么不告诉瑞克
Why didn't you tell Rick?
塔拉 罗西塔 尤金
Tara, Rosita, Eugene?
- 他们为什么没有说 - 我叫他们保密
- Why didn't they…? - I told them to keep quiet about it.
为什么
Why?
我们能忘了这事 翻篇吗
Can we just forget it, move past it?
你没必要背负那事
You don't have to carry that.
什么事
Carry what?
你知道我做了什么
You know what I did.
你不想告诉别人
You don't want to tell anyone, it…
好像你也做了一样
It's kind of like you did it, too.
才不是
No, it's not.
走吧
Just go.
（山姆·安德森）
《行尸走肉》
我们可以跟山顶寨合作
And we can work with the Hilltop.
玛姬谈定了一笔交易
Maggie hammered out a deal.
他们为我们提供食物
We're getting food…
鸡蛋 黄油 新鲜蔬菜
Eggs, butter, fresh vegetables.
但他们不是白送的
But they're not just giving it away.
这些救世军
These Saviors,
差点在路上杀了萨沙 达里尔和亚伯拉罕
they almost killed Sasha, Daryl, and Abraham on the road.
他们迟早会找到我们
Now, sooner or later, they would've found us,
就跟狼群一样
Just like those Wolves did,
跟耶稣一样
Just like Jesus did.
他们会杀死我们中的一个或几个
They would killed someone or some of us.
然后他们会试图支配我们
And then they would try to own us.
而我们会试图阻止他们
And we would try to stop them.
但到了那个时候 在那种战斗中
But by then, in that kind of fight,
我们粮食短缺 可能会输
low on food, we could lose.
这是唯一一种能尽可能地
This is the only way to be sure,
确保我们取胜的方式
as sure as we can get, that we win.
我们必须赢
And we have to win.
我们只有帮山顶寨这个忙
We do this for the Hilltop,
才能保护这里
it's how we keep this place.
才能养活这里
It's how we feed this place.
这件事得集体表决
This needs to be a group decision.
假如有人反对
If anybody objects,
现在就是你们发表意见的机会
here's your chance to say your piece.
你确定我们能取胜吗
You're sure we can do it?
我们可以打败他们吗
We can beat them?
凭借我们做过的事 我们学到的东西
What this group has done, what we've learned,
我们所成为的人 我们所有人…
what we've become, all of us…
没错 我确定
Yes, I'm sure.
那我们只用告诉他们这一点就行了
Then all we have to do is just tell them that.
他们是不会妥协的
Well, they don't compromise.
这不是要他们妥协
This isn't a compromise.
这是给他们一个选择
It's a choice you give them.
是一条出路 对他们和对我们都是如此
It's a way out, for them and for us.
假如我们试着去和救世军谈
We try and talk to the Saviors,
那我们就放弃了我们的先机和安全
we give up our advantage, our safety.
不行 我们得在他们找上门之前抢先出击
No, we have to come for them before they come for us.
我们不能让他们活着
We can't leave them alive.
只要有生命 便有可能性
Where there's life, there's possibility.
有他们攻击我们的可能性
Of them hitting us.
我们不是必须这样做
We're not trapped in this.
你们没有一个人必须这样做
None of you are trapped in this.
摩根…
Morgan…
他们总是会回来的
They always come back.
他们死后也会回来的
Come back when they're dead, too.
没错 到时我们会阻止它们
Yeah, we'll stop them.
我们之前就阻止过
We have before.
我说的不是行尸
I'm not talking about the walkers.
摩根想要先和他们谈谈
Morgan wants to talk to them first.
我觉得那是个错误
I think that would be a mistake,
但这不取决于我
but it's not up to me.
我会和那些待在家中的人谈谈
I'll talk to the people still at home.
也会和现在正在放哨的人讨论
I'll discuss it with the people on guard now, too,
但这里还有没有人想要先和救世军接触
but who else wants to approach the Saviors,
和他们谈谈
talk to them first?
这个地方发生过的事
What happened here,
我们不会让它再次发生了
we won't let that happen again.
我不会
I won't.
那就定了
Looks like it's settled.
我们很清楚这是怎么一回事
We know exactly what this is.
我们不回避它 才能生存
We don't shy from it, we live.
我们要把他们杀光
We kill them all.
不是所有人都得动手杀人
We don't all have to kill.
但选择留在这里的人
But if people are gonna stay here…
必须接受这一点
they do have to accept it.
（瑞恩 凯伦 大卫 丽兹）
（终点站/院子 3）
（蜡烛女 4）
（狼群 7）
（共计18）
需要有人在周边放哨
We need someone on the perimeter keeping watch.
我可以去
That could be me.
这样才安全
That would be safe.
更安全
Safer.
现在再安全也不安全
Whatever safer looks like now.
是啊
Yeah.
交易是我谈的
I made that deal.
虽然不是我的主意 但却牵连了大家
It wasn't my idea, but I led us into this.
我必须去
I have to come.
那东西会要你的命
Those things'll kill you.
还有多余的吗
You got another one?
没你的份
Not for you.
为什么
And why is that?
因为你是混蛋
'cause, asshole.
好吧
okay.
你也睡不着吗
Couldn't sleep either?
我什么时候睡着过
I never could sleep.
我很担心明天的事
Worried about tomorrow.
你去吗
You going?
不去
No.
是你要去
You are.
你做出的事
You can do things that…
能把我吓死
That just terrify me.
为什么
How?
你觉得我为什么做得到
How do you think I do those things?
你是位母亲
You're a mom.
以前是
I was.
现在也是
You are.
我…
It… it…
我不是说饼干和微笑
It's not the cookies or the smiles.
而是
It's…
棘手的事
It's the hard stuff.
可怕的事
The scary stuff.
所以你才做得到
It's how you can do it.
这是力量
It's strength.
在大多数人的心中 你是位母亲
You're a mom to most of the people here.
在你心中也是吗
To you, too?
不
No.
你在我心中很特别
You're something else to me.
还没到明天呢
Well, it's not tomorrow yet.
就开始收拾了吗
Packing your stilettos?
我们只离开一个晚上
We'll only be gone a night.
我去了
I'm going.
我也去 但是明天才去
I am, too, but tomorrow.
我走了
I'm leaving.
为什么
Why?
就这样发生了
It happens.
你当真要走
Are you serious?
这是我所希望的
This is how I want it.
- 为什么 - 为什么红果莓是棕色的呢
- Why? - Why are dingleberries brown?
哪有那么多狗屁理由
It's just the way shit is.
不 不 我们经历了这么多
No, no. After everything we've been through,
你不许一走了之 除非告诉我理由
you are not walking out that door unless you can tell me why.
告诉我
Tell me!
告诉我理由
Tell me why!
第一次见到你的时候
When I first met you,
我以为你是地球上最后一个女人
I thought you were the last woman on Earth.
但你不是
You're not.
你尝过这个吗 很有嚼头
You try one of these? They're chewy.
有点…
They, uh…
劲道
got some fight in them.
描述一下
Describe it.
长方形的建筑 顶部有个大接收器
Rectangular building, big satellites on it.
有窗户吗
Any windows?
我不记得了
I don't remember any.
我想他们只给那地方留了一个入口
I think they made it so there's only one way in.
门口有守卫吗
Guards outside?
有 至少两个
Yeah, two of them, at least.
你不知道他们有多少人
And you don't know how many people they have?
不知道
No.
不知道 我看到过一个储存食物的地方
I mean, no. I saw a place where they stored food.
里面不大 所以
It wasn't that big, so…
- 你进去过吗 - 是的
- You've been inside? - Yeah.
他们让我们搬过一次补给品
They had us load in supplies one time.
你记得什么
What do you remember?
你担心吗
Are you worried?
不
No.
不担心 只是…
No, it's just…
我爱你 走之前我想说出来…
I love you, and I just wanted to say it before…
你不用回应我
you don't have to say it back.
- 那个… - 等你回来我再回应你
- It's… - I'll say it when you come back.
希斯和我还得再出去两周
Heath and I are still going on that two-weeker.
我们就从那里出发
We're gonna leave from there.
你想一起走吗
Do you want to come?
我可以改计划 不用从基地走
I mean, I can change it so we don't leave from the compound.
我们可以回来 从这里走
We could come back and we could leave from here.
- 我们要拿些药品 所以… - 我不能去
- You know, we're gonna get meds, so… - I can't.
- 我得留在这 - 好
- No, I didn't… I'm… I just… I need to be here. - Yeah.
现在我是唯一的医生
I'm the only doctor now.
所以我不能去
So I can't.
好的
Yeah.
但我很想去
But I want to.
等你回来我会回应你的
I'll tell you when you come back.
好的
Yeah.
你没看到其他房间吗
And you didn't see any other rooms?
没有 地方很大
No, it's a big place.
这是我看到的那条走廊
This is the hallway I saw.
还有更多
There is more.
每次他们都让你们把东西搬到这里
And every time, they had you bring things into here?
天啊
Jesus.
我们带过一些长矛给他们
We brought a couple spears for them.
两个救世军沿着这条走廊把东西带进去
Two of the Saviors took them down this hallway.
他们一定是做了什么
Now, they must've done something with them.
因为他们没把东西带回来
because they didn't come back with them.
也许是个武器柜 军械库
Maybe a weapons locker, an armory.
好的
Okay.
我们进去 守住军械库
We get in there, secure the armory,
就能终结战斗
that's how we end it.
当时卡萝尔在这里也是这么做的
That's how Carol ended it here.
但他们是否有军械库
But we don't know if they have an armory.
甚至在哪我们都不知道
or where it even is.
我们有很多可靠的推测
Well, we've got a lot of good guesses.
靠更少的情报我们都成功过
We've done more with less.
我们晚上趁他们睡觉时潜入
We go in at night while they're sleeping.
守卫不会睡觉的
The guards won't be sleeping.
正如我说 我认为只有一条路进去
Like I said, I think there's only one way in.
没办法在不吵醒其他人的情况下
and there's no way to bust through that door.
直接从那扇门突入
without waking up the rest of them.
不用吵醒他们
We don't need to.
他们会开门让我们进去的
They're going to open it for us, let us walk right in.
他们要格雷戈里的人头 对吧
They want Gregory's head, right?
我们就给他们
We're gonna give it to them.
亚伦 罗西塔
Aaron, Rosita.
你们从这开始
You start here.
我们每四分之一英里就分头行动
We'll peel off every quarter mile,
几小时后来这会合
meet back here in a couple of hours.
看看有什么收获
See what we got.
现在没法回头了
There's no turning back now.
我可以走
I could walk.
也许能跑一小段 也许能跑很久
Maybe run a little, maybe a lot.
我哪都不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我想学习 你教我是有原因的
I wanted to learn and you taught me for a reason.
你为什么还穿成这样
Why are you still wearing that?
我觉得 我还是我自己
It's still who I was. I think.
而且他们很难在黑暗中看到我
And it'll be harder for them to see me in the dark.
我差点就在会上跟大家说了
I almost told everyone at the meeting.
我们不能告诉他们
We're not telling them.
摩根在教堂里站出来
Morgan stood up in that church.
试图说服我们不要这样做
and tried to talk us out of this.
那又怎样
What's wrong with that?
也许他不知道他在说什么
Maybe that he didn't know what the hell he's talking about?
我们没把他藏匿
That he should take the win.
那个精神病的事抖出来 他就应该知足
that we didn't kick his ass out for hiding that psychopath.
如果我们跟所有人说
If we told everyone,
他们也会知道丹妮斯的事 你知道的
they'd find out about Denise, you know that.
那个婊子养的想站在那
That hijo de puta tried to stand there.
表现得好像我们不知道我们…
and act like we didn't know what we were…
他不想杀人
He doesn't want to kill.
我们也不想杀人 也不喜欢
We don't want to kill. We don't like it.
但就这样发生了
It happens.
我不会跟人说的
I'm not telling anyone.
觉得如何
What do you think?
也许可以
Maybe.
如果我们剪一下头发
If we, um, cut the hair…
修一下胡子
trim the beard.
如果天黑了
If it's dark.
我们要杀了那些人
We're gonna kill those people.
就今晚
Tonight.
我一直很幸运
Look, I've been lucky.
我之前都没必要这样做
I haven't had to do it before.
你呢
Have you?
我也一直很幸运
I've been lucky, too.
你紧张吗
You nervous?
你经历过那种…
Have you ever seen something that, um…
经历过之后 你…
afterwards, you…
你根本不想睡觉
you didn't want to sleep.
你根本不饿 因为当你闭上眼睛
and you weren't hungry because when you close your eyes.
就会浮现在眼前的事
you could see it?
- 当你试图去吃东西… - 有过
- And when you try to eat… - Yeah.
我也是
Me, too.
杀人肯定比这感觉糟多了
Killing somebody has gotta be worse than that.
肯定更糟
It has to be.
所以没错
So, yeah…
我很紧张
I'm nervous.
对于这一切 伙计
For the whole thing, man.
对于这一切都是
For the whole thing.
我们要去四周看看
We're gonna take a look around,
摸清楚那里到底有多少人
try to get a feel for how many people are in there.
如果我们觉得可行 就潜入
We like how it looks, we go in.
黎明前的那几个小时
A couple of hours before dawn.
外面的守卫也倦了
The guards outside'll be tired.
里面的人都在睡觉
Everyone inside'll be sleeping.
如果感觉形势不对就撤退 重订计划
We don't like what we see, we head back, make a new plan.
他们不知道我们是谁
They don't know who we are.
我们要让耶稣躲在暗处
We'll keep Jesus in the shadows.
这就是我们的生存方式
This is how we eat.
我们半夜出发
We roll out at midnight.
玛姬怎么也来了
Why is Maggie here?
她负责在周边放哨
She's guarding the perimeter.
好吧 但她为什么会来
Yeah, but why is she here?
因为这是她的选择
'Cause it's her choice.
我想跟她一起待在外面
I want to stay out there with her.
我们必须率先夺取军械库
Well, this whole thing's a race to the armory.
我们需要尽可能多的人一起进去
We need as many people inside as we can get.
她不该一个人在外面
She shouldn't be out there alone.
她一开始就不该来
She shouldn't be out here in the first place.
好吧
Okay.
很好
Good.
她把头发弄好了吗
She's done with the hair?
现在是什么情况
What've we got?
- 那个 - 就那个
- That one. - That's it.
好吧
All right.
还好我们是晚上行动
Though, it's probably good we're doing this at night.
有什么问题吗
Something wrong with it?
鼻子 格雷戈里的鼻子形状不一样
The nose. Gregory's is a different shape.
他反抗了
He fought back.
他打断了你的手 对吧
He broke your hand, right?
看来没必要追究细节了
Guess there's no reason to be subtle about it.
怎么了
What?
救世军很可怕 但是…
The Saviors, they're scary, but …
那帮混球跟你比差远了
those pricks got nothing on you.
停在那
Stop right there!
报上名来 混蛋
Announce yourself, asshole!
我是山顶寨的埃迪
It's Eddie from Hilltop!
任务已完成
It's done!
出来
Step out!
是他的头吗
Is that it?
是的
Yeah!
拿过来 蠢货
Bring it here, shit brain!
从袋子里拿出来 小牙签
I don't want the bag, needle dick.
看看这狗东西
Will you look at this shit?
他打断了我的手 我打断了他的鼻子
He broke my hand. I broke his nose.
所以他看起来是这样的
That's why he looks that way.
小贱人打断了我的鼻子
Little bitch broke my nose.
好吧 看来你长教训了
Okay, looks like you learned.
我放了你的人 你回家
I'll get your guy, you'll go home,
下周多带点贡品过来 知道吗
and you bring us more stuff next week, hmm?
瞧瞧谁来了
Well, well, well. Look who it is.
没事 没事
It's okay, it's okay.
我们带你回家 带你回家
We're bringing you back. We're bringing you back.
检查门 找到军械库
Check the doors. Find the arsenal.
我们去干掉他们
We take them out.
你还是神父吗
You still a priest?
瑞克和卡尔教我用枪
Rick and Carl taught me about guns,
还有其他武器
other weapons.
教我怎么出一份力
How to contribute.
我还是神父
I'm still a priest.
今天早上我对我女朋友撒谎了
I lied to my girlfriend this morning.
我… 她发现我在想事
I, um… she caught me thinking about something,
所以我告诉她我爱她
so I told her that I loved her.
我第一次对她这样说
For the first time.
我这么对她说是为了隐瞒一些事情
That's how I told her, covering something up.
你在隐瞒什么
What were you covering?
我以前做过这种事
That I'd done something like this before.
我并不喜欢
That I didn't like it.
是吗
Do you?
你爱她吗
Do you love her?
是的
Yeah.
那你知道自己是为什么而战了
So, you know what you're fighting for.
藏宝室
Honeypot.
他们有麻烦了 待在这
They're in trouble. Stay here.
- 我和你一块去 - 我说了待在这
- I'm going with you. - I said stay here.
不行
No.
该死 玛姬
Damn it, Maggie.
- 我必须去 - 不 你不必
- I have to. - No, you don't. You don't have to.
是的 我必须去
Yes, I do.
你到底来这里做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
那我应该做什么
What am I supposed to do?
你应该做个母亲
You're supposed to be someone else.
他们需要我们的帮助
They need our help.
你必须留在这里
You are staying here.
我们得走了 送他们回山顶寨
We need to go. Get them back to the Hilltop.
什么 你们的人可能有危险
What? Your people could be in trouble.
如果你带他们回去 交易依然有效 对吗
If you get them back, the deal's still on, right?
对吗
Right?
他们能自己回去
If they get themselves back.
安迪 送他们回山顶寨
Andy, drive him back to the Hilltop.
听着 如果他们看到你 而我们没成功
Look, if they see you and we don't make it…
我们会成功的 他们不会看到我的
We're gonna make it. And they're not gonna see me.
你是认真的吗
Are you kidding?
走
Go!
不是我们死 就是你们亡
If it wasn't us, it was gonna be you.
搞什么
The hell?
这是上锁的房间之一 我掩护你 上吧
That's one of the locked ones. I'm gonna cover you. Do it.
快走
Come on!
这就是新世界
So, this is the next world.
放下枪
Drop it.
你
You, uh…
你会杀我吗 神父
You gonna kill me, Padre?
神父
Padre?
你们心里不要忧愁
"Let not your heart be troubled."
你跟我一样死定了
You're just as dead as me.
在我父的家里 有许多住处
"In my father's house are many mansions.
若是没有 我就早已告诉你们了
If it were not so, I would've told you."
你们都死定了
You're all dead.
- 我若去为你们预备了地方 - 要见血了
- "I go prepare a place for you." - Blood's coming.
阿门
Amen.
你想跟我们回家吗
Hey, you want to just come back with us?
休息几天 再和塔拉出去
Take a couple days before you and Tara go out again?
不了老兄 我只想尽快离开这里
No, man. I just want to get out of here.
怎么了
What is it?
我只是
Just…
我只是想知道他们中哪个是尼根
Just want to know which one of them was Negan.
狗杂种
Son of a bitch!
你是从哪里搞到摩托的
Where'd you get the bike?
杀了我吧
Just do it!
就像你们杀了其他人一样 对吧
Like you did everyone else, right?
放下武器 混蛋
Lower your gun, prick.
拿着柯尔特蟒蛇左轮的那个
You, with the Colt Python.
你们所有人 立刻放下武器
All of you, lower your weapons right now.
出来
Come on out.
我们谈谈
Let's talk.
我们不会出来 但我们会谈谈
We're not coming out, but we will talk.
卡萝尔和玛姬在我们手上
We've got a Carol and a Maggie.
我想你们应该想谈谈这个
I'm thinking that's something you want to chat about.